(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
November 4th 21:00 LIVE START! 重大告知ライブ
November 4th 21:00 LIVE START! Major Announcement Live
Starring 星街すいせい
Starring Hoshimachi Suisei
LIVE START
だって僕は星じゃないから
Because I'm not a star...
Stellar Stellar 作詞：星街すいせい / 作曲：TAKU INOUE
Stellar Stellar Lyrics: Hoshimachi Suisei / Composition: TAKU INOUE
きっと君はもう気付いていた
I'm sure you had already noticed
僕の心の奥で描いた
What I drew deep inside my heart
それがこれから話す陳腐な
That is the hackneyed...
モノローグさ
...monologue I'm about to tell
ずっと言えない言葉があった
There were words I could never say
壊せない壁だったんだ
They were a wall I couldn't break
ずっとさ
All this time
ふっと香る排気ガスの匂いが
The sudden scent of exhaust fumes
どうしようもなく憎らしくて
I hated it so much I couldn't help it
部屋の隅で膝を抱えて
Crouched in the corner of my room
震えていた
I was trembling
太陽なんていらないから
I don't need the sun
明けないでいて
So please, don't let the dawn break
その手を伸ばして
Stretch out your hand
誰かに届くように
So it can reach someone
僕だって君と同じ
I'm just the same as you
特別なんかじゃないから
I'm not special at all
何者かになりたくて
I just wanted to be someone
そうさ僕は夜を歌う Stellar Stellar
That's right, I sing of the night, Stellar Stellar
ありったけの輝き放って
Emitting all the radiance I have
呼ぶ声はずっとずっと止まない
The calling voices will never, ever stop
そうさ僕はずっと泣きたかったのは
That's right, the one I've always wanted to cry for
待ってるシンデレラじゃないさ
Isn't the waiting Cinderella
迎えに行く王子様だ
But the Prince going to get her
だって僕は星じゃないから
Because I'm not a star...
なんてありふれた話なんだ
What a common story it is
いつまで書き連ねていた
How long was I writing it out?
ノートの隅に眠るほんのワンシーンだ
It's just a single scene sleeping in the corner of a notebook
きっとあの星も泣いてるんだ
I'm sure that star is crying too
明日なんて来ないままでいて
So let tomorrow never come
その手を伸ばして
Stretch out your hand
誰かに届くように
So it can reach someone
本当に大切なものは
The things that are truly important
目に見えないみたいなんだ
Seem to be invisible to the eye
そうさ僕は夜を歌う Stellar Stellar
That's right, I sing of the night, Stellar Stellar
...歌うよ そうさ僕が ずっと 歌いたかったのは
...I'll sing. Yes, what I've always wanted to sing...
ありのままの輝きで
With a brilliance just as it is
今宵 音楽は きっと きっと 止まらない
Tonight, the music surely, surely won't stop
そうさ僕が ずっと 泣きたかったのは
Yes, what I've always wanted to cry about...
会えない きみのせいじゃない さあ 救いに行くヒーローだ
Isn't your fault for not being able to meet. Come, I'm the hero going to save you
夢見がちな おとぎ話
A dreamy fairy tale
おとぎ話
Fairy tale
夢見がちな おとぎ話 終わらせて ほら今
Ending the dreamy fairy tale, look, now
そうさ僕が歌う Stellar Stellar ありのままの輝きで
Yes, I sing, Stellar Stellar, with a brilliance just as it is
今宵 音楽は ずっと ずっと 止まらない
Tonight, the music will go on forever and ever
僕らは そうさ僕が歌う Stellar Stellar 世界の中心で
We are... Yes, I sing, Stellar Stellar, at the center of the world
今宵 音楽は きっと きっと 止まらない
Tonight, the music surely, surely won't stop
そうさ僕が ずっと 願いたかったのは
Yes, what I've always wanted to wish for...
待って シンデレラじゃない さあ 救いに行くのさ
Wait, I'm not Cinderella. Come, I'm going to save you
だって僕は星だから
Because I am a star
そうだ僕は星だった
That's right, I was a star
そうだ僕こそ星だった
That's right, I was the star itself
Stellar Stellar
こんこーめ！ 皆様お久しぶりです！
Kon-comet! Everyone, it's been a while!
彗星の如く現れたスターの原石！ アイドルVTuberの星街すいせいです！
A shooting star, a diamond in the rough! Idol VTuber Hoshimachi Suisei here!
すいちゃんは～！ 今日も可愛い～！
Sui-chan is~! Cute again today~!
うわ～！ お久しぶり、みんな！
Wow~! Long time no see, everyone!
えー、声帯の手術をして参りまして、 1ヶ月半お休みをいただき...
Um, I underwent throat surgery and took a month and a half off...
こんな風に、元に戻りました！ 無事元に戻りました！
And just like this, I'm back to normal! I've safely recovered!
どうですか皆様、すいちゃんの声に 変化ありますか、ありませんか？
How about it everyone? Is there a change in my voice, or not?
どうですか？ 今日も可愛い？ ありがとう！
How is it? Still cute today? Thank you!
ありがとう！ ね、コメント打ってくださってる皆様もね、 スパチャ送ってくださってる皆様も、
Thank you! To everyone writing comments and everyone sending Super Chats,
メンバー入ってくれた皆様も、 ありがとうございます！
And everyone who joined the membership, thank you so much!
高評価、チャンネル登録ぜひお願いいたします。
Please give a like and subscribe to the channel.
ということで、本日は重大告知を引っ提げて 復帰をさせていただくということでね、
So, today I'm making my return with some major announcements,
重大告知がなんだろうかということは、 まぁ最後まで見ていただいて...
As for what those announcements are, well, please watch until the end...
よろしくお願いいたします！
Thank you!
それでは、次の曲に早速行きたいと思います。 バイバーイ！
Now then, let's head straight into the next song. Bye-bye!
HOSHIMACHI SUISEI
STAR GEMSTONE
NEXT MUSIC
TEMPLATE 作詞・作曲：キタニタツヤ
TEMPLATE Lyrics & Composition: Tatsuya Kitani
画面の向こう そのまた向こうで
Beyond the screen, and even further beyond
編まれた言葉たち 殴っても痛まない透明な拳
The words woven there, transparent fists that don't hurt even if they hit
満天の星のように 散らばっている
Scattered like a sky full of stars
ガラスの破片の上を 足引き摺って歩くような痛み
The pain like dragging your feet over glass shards
僕は ずっと 苦しかったんだ
I have been suffering for a long time
そうだ 僕にとって 世界なんてTemplate
That's right, for me, the world is just a Template
この生が正しいか 間違いか 自分で決めるから
Whether this life is right or wrong, I'll decide for myself
そうだ 僕にとって 愛なんてTemplateは邪魔で
That's right, for me, the Template of love is just in the way
鏡に映った僕の色 全部 僕のためにあったのに
All the colors of me reflected in the mirror were for my sake
気付いたら この手を離れていた
But before I knew it, they'd left my hands
名前も顔も隠したのに 眩しい
Even though I hid my name and face, it's dazzling
僕の何がわかるの 輪郭さえ ぼやけそうな火種
What do you know about me? A spark that seems like its outline would blur
僕の全部 獲り戻さなくちゃ
I have to take back everything that's mine
窓さえぎった ノイズほどに鳴るの火花
The sparks that ring out like the noise blocking the window
Ah...
好き放題を殺し、カス以下の種に降っても
Killing self-indulgence, even if it rains on seeds less than trash
のぼる僕は要らない この街の頭上
I don't need the 'me' that rises above this city
降り注いだ慈愛を 拒絶はしない
I won't reject the affection pouring down
僕のこと 痛みも 姿形も
About me, my pain, my form
誰に決められることもない
It won't be decided by anyone
そっと僕にとって世界なんて...
To me, a world like this is just...
この世界 正しさが間違いだ...
In this world, correctness is a mistake...
あの日 放射状の輝きに...
That day, in the radial glow...
蔓延る 虚像よりも
Rather than the spreading illusions
届かなくたって構わない 僕以外何も要らない
I don't care if it doesn't reach, I don't need anything but myself
ふっと弾けた感情に
To the emotions that suddenly burst
言い訳を並べて過ごした
I spent time lining up excuses
葛藤も知らない街角に
In a street corner that doesn't know conflict
君だけだって嘯いた
I boasted that there was only you
信じたくもないままで踊っている
Dancing while not even wanting to believe
殺すために連ね続けた言葉
Words I kept stringing together in order to kill
見えないの僕が
Can't you see me?
僕のこの声が聞こえてる
Can you hear this voice of mine?
Dancer in the silhouette
すらも透明できっと無骨だけれど
Even that's transparent and surely clumsy
でも せめて声を鳴らそう
But at least let's make a sound
指にしがみついてもずっと証明を
Even if I cling to my fingers, forever the proof...
見逃すなよ 痛いんだ
Don't miss it, it hurts
散々恨んだ 明るいストロボ
The bright strobe lights I've hated so much
意味ありげに伸びていく影
Shadows stretching out as if they mean something
淡々と過ぎた 一粒の
At a single word that passed by indifferently
君の言葉で泣きたくなった
I felt like crying at your word
大切にしたいものが零れていく
The things I want to treasure are spilling away
記すために綴り続けたい言葉
Words I want to keep writing in order to record
見えてるの僕が
Can you see me?
僕のこの声が聞こえてる
Can you hear this voice of mine?
Dancer in the silhouette
すらも透明できっと不器用だけれど
Even that's transparent and surely clumsy
でも だから叫んで 喘いで
So I shout and I pant
正しのまま走れねぇ 気づいて
I can't run while remaining 'correct', notice me
教えてよ 答えを
Tell me the answer
こんな僕の心まで奪い去って
Take away even a heart like mine
灰色の街が笑っても　もう足取りも重くなる
Even if the grey city laughs, my steps are getting heavier
声を枯らして叫んで足掻いて裸足で走り続けて
Screaming until my voice goes hoarse, struggling, running barefoot
変わらないように　嫌われないように
So that I don't change, so that I won't be hated
戸惑い続けてるだけだ
I'm just continuing to be lost
見つけてよ僕を
Please find me
僕のこの声が聞こえてる？
Can you hear this voice of mine?
点在だったシルエットさえも透明になってきっと
Even the scattered silhouettes will surely become transparent
虚構を叫べど　でもせめて声を
Even if I scream out a fiction, at least let my voice...
枯らそう　必死に縋ってもずっと
Go hoarse, even if I cling on desperately forever
証明を願うのさ　いたいよ
I'll wish for proof, it hurts
バイバイレイニー
作詞・作曲：堀江晶太
Bye Bye Rainy
Lyrics & Composition: Shota Horie
クラップサイド　乾いた正装
Clap side, dry formal wear
ガラガラ透けた　右はサスペンダー
Empty and transparent, suspenders on the right
どんな言葉にもちゃんと綻びがあった
Every word had its own flaw
光彩も言わずにアッソー
Not even mentioning the brilliance, "I see"
どうでもいい朝になれすぎて
I've become too accustomed to these trivial mornings
傘は持ってない　感じてた未来
I don't have an umbrella, the future I felt
返しけず　交わしけず　ガラガラ
Unable to return it, unable to dodge it, empty
街行く　よそ者
Strangers passing through the city
ねぇ独りだった　壊せたのはレイニー
Hey, I was alone, what I could break was Rainy
レイニー　君を連れ出さないで
Rainy, don't take you away
悲しくはないよ　嬉しくもないよ　レイニー
I'm not sad, nor am I happy, Rainy
レイニー　よく晴れた鈍色へ
Rainy, towards the clear dark grey
限定式の　嘘を染めるレイニー
A limited formula, Rainy dyes the lies
レイニー　こんな間違いだらけで
Rainy, in a place so full of mistakes
リリース一歩のパノラマ　レイニー　レイニー
A panorama one step away from release, Rainy, Rainy
今日は何点だったろ？
I wonder what the score was today?
バイバイ　バイバイ　よく晴れた鈍色の証拠
Bye bye, bye bye, proof of the clear dark grey
空をクラクション　操ってお目見え
Manipulating the car horns in the sky, making an appearance
光買ったなら　染めてよくだけ
If you bought light, just dye it better
泣いて泣いて泣いて残った
What remained after crying and crying and crying
パスパス今日も明日も来ないだろう
Passing, passing, today and tomorrow probably won't come
喧騒　五分の　素直な声
Five minutes of clamor, an honest voice
夢中の裏
Behind being engrossed
白い煙に吹かれながら歌う
Singing while being blown by white smoke
救いのない甘い事
Sweet things with no salvation
ねぇ独りだった　壊せたのはレイニー
Hey, I was alone, what I could break was Rainy
レイニー　そんな透明なキス
Rainy, such a transparent kiss
確かな声に　似ている青にバイバイ
To the blue that resembles a certain voice, bye bye
バイバイ　しなくちゃいけないの
Bye bye, I have to do it
ほんの僅かに　雨の合間に
Just for a moment, in between the rain
君も行くなら　道中を祈ってる
If you're going too, I'll pray for your journey
無事を祈ってる
I'll pray for your safety
ねぇ独りだった　壊せたのはレイニー
Hey, I was alone, what I could break was Rainy
レイニー　君を連れ出さないで
Rainy, don't take you away
悲しくはないよ　嬉しくもないよ　レイニー
I'm not sad, nor am I happy, Rainy
レイニー　よく晴れた鈍色へ
Rainy, towards the clear dark grey
限定式の　嘘を染めるレイニー
A limited formula, Rainy dyes the lies
レイニー　こんな間違いだらけで
Rainy, in a place so full of mistakes
リリース一歩のパノラマ　レイニー　レイニー
A panorama one step away from release, Rainy, Rainy
今日は何点だったよ？　バイバイ　バイバイ
I wonder what the score was today? Bye bye, bye bye
...a little bit of the rhythm
Bye bye...
はい！
Yes!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
続けて三曲、私のオリジナルソング
Continuing with three of my original songs,
「TEMPLATE」「GHOST」「バイバイレイニー」を、
"TEMPLATE", "GHOST", and "Bye Bye Rainy",
ダンサーさん引き連れて歌って踊らせていただきました。
I performed them together with my dancers.
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
いやダンサーさんがね、いるだけでもう花が添えられて、
Having the dancers here really adds so much flair,
あの、とても助かりました。
it was a huge help.
皆さん本当にありがとう！
Thank you all so much!
ダンサーさんいつもありがとう！
Dancers, thank you as always!
はい、ということで皆さんいかがだったでしょうか。
Well then, how did everyone like it?
「かっけー」ありがとう！
"So cool", thank you!
ちゃんとコメント見えております。「かっけー」ありがとう。
I can see the comments clearly. "So cool", thank you.
「おかえりすいちゃん」ありがとうございます。
"Welcome back, Suichan!", thank you very much.
ということで、
Now then,
次からはゲストパートなので、
from here on is the guest part,
ゲストが来ますよ。
so a guest is coming.
さて、ゲストは誰かな？誰かな？
I wonder who the guest is? Who could it be?
あの人だ！
It's that person!
次のステージへ、バイバイ！
To the next stage, bye-bye!
HOSHIMACHI SUISEI
STAR GEMSTONE
NEXT MUSIC
本日のスペシャルゲスト、
Today's special guest,
TAKU INOUEさんが来てくれました！
TAKU INOUE is here with us!
イエーイ！
Yay!
陽気なおじさんがDJしてくれますよ！
This cheerful guy is going to DJ for us!
TONIGHT BRAND ORCHESTRAから
From TONIGHT BRAND ORCHESTRA,
陽気なナンバーを聴いてください。
please listen to this upbeat number.
アレグロ！
Allegro!
ハロー ハロー ハロー
Hello, hello, hello
幕はもう開いてるんだ ずっと
The curtain has been open for a long time
今
Now
真空さえ 揺らして 響かせる そんな
Shaking even the vacuum, resonating such
音楽を
music
さぁ いつの間にかステップを
Now, before I knew it, taking a step
踏み出しながら超えろ borders
stepping out and crossing borders
アレグロで今日も待って
Waiting today as well, in Allegro
大人たちの交渉は不都合
Adult negotiations are inconvenient
いけない一歩 もっと継いで
Take another forbidden step, keep it going
ぶち鳴らせ 今日も待って
Let it ring out, waiting today as well
で
with
手が放物線 ずっと
My hands follow a parabola, forever
煌めいていけるように
so that I can keep on sparkling
テンポ速めて
Speeding up the tempo
最速でドアを叩いた
I knocked on the door at top speed
すべて異常天候 きっと
All unusual weather, surely
君まで届くような
reaching all the way to you
時代の声はもうすぐ
The voice of the era is almost here
手が放物線 ずっと
My hands follow a parabola, forever
煌めいていけるように
so that I can keep on sparkling
テンポ速めて
Speeding up the tempo
最速でドアを叩いた
I knocked on the door at top speed
すべて異常天候 きっと
All unusual weather, surely
君まで届くような
reaching all the way to you
音楽を
Music
さぁ いつの間にかステップを
Now, before I knew it, taking a step
踏み出しながら超えろ borders
stepping out and crossing borders
激動ハイコー
Turbulent high-call
最低な深呼吸でしょ
It's the worst kind of deep breath, right?
止まない衝動
An unstopping urge
新たな一歩 もっと継いで
Take a new step, keep it going
アレグロで今日も待って
Waiting today as well, in Allegro
イェイ
Yeah
輝け夜のセッション バイ
Shine on, night session bye
アレグロで今日も待って
Waiting today as well, in Allegro
高速じゃ足りない
High speed isn't enough
もうすぐ迫ってるランデブー
The rendezvous is fast approaching
フルスロットル向かってる　月が満ちるまで
Heading at full throttle until the moon is full
時間はもうない
There's no more time
まだ君を待ってる　勝ってる　なんか歌っては笑ってる
I'm still waiting for you, winning, singing and laughing
余裕なんてないくせにさ
Even though I have no room to spare
高速じゃ足りない　足りない　君とじゃ足りない　足りない
High speed isn't enough, not enough, with you it's not enough, not enough
逃げ切るよ明日　明日　君に見せたいから
I'll make it through tomorrow, tomorrow, because I want to show you
夜はまだ明けない　明けない　夢はまだ覚めない　覚めない
The night won't end yet, won't end, the dream won't break yet, won't break
さあ今前へ
Now, move forward
凹凸のハイウェイ　飛ばして　大きめの一歩で once again
Speeding down the bumpy highway, taking a big step once again
月が満ちるまで　あと百十五秒
Until the moon is full, another 115 seconds
今フルスロットル向かってる　下向かないように走ってる
Heading at full throttle now, running so I don't look down
悩んでる暇はない
There's no time to worry
高速でめぐり　めぐり　今度こそ make it make it
Going round and round at high speed, this time I'll make it, make it
逃げ出そう今夜　今夜　君をさらってから
Let's escape tonight, tonight, after I take you away
夜はまだ明けない　明けない　夢はまだ覚めない　覚めない
The night won't end yet, won't end, the dream won't break yet, won't break
さあ今前へ
Now, move forward
空を駆けて
Run through the sky
高速じゃ足りない
High speed isn't enough
未来の世界へ
To the future world
高速じゃ足りない　足りない　到着でもう一回
High speed isn't enough, it's not enough, one more time upon arrival
追いついた今日は　今日は　君と見ていたいから
I finally caught up today, today, because I want to see it with you
夜はまだ明けない　明けない　夢はまだ覚めない　覚めない
The night won't end yet, won't end, the dream won't break yet, won't break
さあ今前へ
Now, move forward
時を越えて
Across time
それでは、次の曲聞いてください、コメットメドレー！
And now, please listen to the next song, Comet Medley!
あの空で輝いた　流れ星を追いかけて
Chasing the shooting star that shone in that sky
いつか君を照らすから　彗星のスターライト
Because I'll shine on you someday, comet starlight
生まれたばかりの小さな光は
The small light that has just been born
消えてしまいそうな声で　歌を歌ったんだ
Sang a song with a voice that seemed about to vanish
誰かに届くようにと　その声を振り絞って
Squeezing out that voice so it would reach someone
今はまだ響かないけど　いつかその心に
It doesn't resonate yet, but someday in that heart
満天の星を降らせよう　眩いほど煌めくよ
Let's make a sky full of stars rain down, they'll sparkle so brightly
何もかも忘れるくらい　とびきりのステージをあげる
I'll give you an extraordinary stage, enough to make you forget everything
今夜は眠れないほどに　胸を躍らせて
Make your heart dance so much you can't sleep tonight
手を取って　さあ行こう　彗星のスターライト
Take my hand, let's go, comet starlight
叶えたい願いを
The wishes I want to come true,
浮かべた光は
the floating light
ずっと出会いを待ってる
has been waiting for a meeting all this time.
早く見つけてよ
Find me quickly.
理想描いただけじゃきっとまだ進めない
Just imagining ideals won't let me move forward.
踏み出したばかりだけど
I've only just taken the first step,
いつかその心に
but someday in that heart,
満開の華を咲かせよ
let's make flowers bloom in full glory.
夢中にさせてみせるから
I'll make you fall head over heels,
次元さえも超えるくらい
so much so that we cross through dimensions.
とびきりのドリームを
An extraordinary dream,
あげる今夜は覚めないで
I'll give you. Don't wake up tonight.
一度きりの瞬間だって大事なの
Even a once-in-a-lifetime moment is precious.
ほら行くよ 彗星のスターライト
Here we go! Starlight of the comet.
数えきれないほどの星が
Countless stars
蠢めき違う色で光っている
shimmer and glow in different colors.
んだ その中で私は
In the midst of that, what kind of
何が残せるのかな きっと
mark can I leave? Surely,
誰よりも蒼く 強い光を
a blue and stronger light than anyone else.
満天の星を降らせよ
Let's make a sky full of stars rain down.
眩いほど煌めくよ
It will sparkle blindingly.
何もかも忘れるくらい とびきりのステージを
To the point of forgetting everything, an extraordinary stage!
満天の星を降らせよ
Let's make a sky full of stars rain down.
眩いほど煌めくよ
It will sparkle blindingly.
何もかも忘れるくらい とびきりのステージを
To the point of forgetting everything, an extraordinary stage!
あげる今夜は眠れない
I'll give you. I can't sleep tonight.
踊り回るほど踊らせて
Let's dance until we're spinning around.
私のこと見ていてね 彗星のスターライト
Keep your eyes on me, Starlight of the comet.
彗星のスターライト
Starlight of the comet.
アンチグラビティ・ガール
Anti-gravity Girl
作詞：MCTC／作曲・編曲：TAKU INOUE
Lyrics: MCTC / Composition & Arrangement: TAKU INOUE
Yeah!
鼻がツンとしそうなほど西日が差して
The evening sun shines so bright my nose might sting,
また迷子になって下らして風引いて
getting lost again, wandering and catching a cold.
探すよ今日もちょっとおかしな色した
Today too, I'm looking for the dream fragments
ガラクタみたいな夢のパーツを
that look like junk with slightly odd colors.
虹色のコクピットで見よう見まねで
In the rainbow-colored cockpit, I imitate and
不鮮明なネジを回して指切って
turn unclear screws, cutting my fingers.
でたらめなメロディ スケッチもなくて
Haphazard melodies, without even a sketch,
それでも鼓動揺らして空を飛んでみたい
but still, shaking my heartbeat, I want to try flying in the sky.
思わず飛んでみたいんだ
I just want to try flying.
今夜のスペシャルゲスト、この方！
Tonight's special guest, this person!
いつか 0（ゼロ）から 10（じゅう）まで
Someday, from 0 to 10,
見たことないスピードで君も乗せて
carrying you at a speed you've never seen before,
夢中な 逆さだってさ 今までの
enthralled, even upside down, from everything
全部を 解いていたい 暴きたい
so far, I want to unravel, I want to expose it all.
止まらない ソワソワ ドキドキしちゃうな
I can't stop, getting all fidgety and heart-pounding.
弾みも無く全部を落として間違えて
Dropping everything without a bounce and making mistakes.
晴れ渡った...
It was clear...
...転んでお空を見上げた。
...I fell down and looked up at the sky.
そろそろ時間だ　準備はもうできてる。
It's almost time, I'm already prepared.
あなたの体まで...
Down to your body...
Ahh...
今夜、アンデッドまで嘘みたいな...
Tonight, even the undead seem like a lie...
...ルートを見つけたいの。
...I want to find the route.
...見つけたの。
...I found it.
ポンコツだって、承知だって...
Even if it's junk, even if I know...
...迷っても止まっても。
...even if I hesitate or stop.
笑ってたい。
I want to keep laughing.
笑ってたい！
I want to keep laughing!
まるでファンタジー...
Just like a fantasy...
素晴らしい日々だなぁ。
What wonderful days.
我が儘だ。
I'm selfish.
探してたんだよ。
I've been looking for it.
夢中、夢中さ。
Absorbed, I'm absorbed.
Ahh...
今夜、アンデッドまで...
Tonight, even the undead...
...まだ知らない...
...to a place still unknown...
...場所まで君も乗せて。
...bringing you along as well.
重力なんて知らない...
I don't know anything about gravity...
...振りほどいてもいい...
...it's okay to shake it off...
...このまま。
...just like this.
有頂天な方だってさ。
They say it's an ecstatic way.
これからの全部も...
From now on, everything...
笑いたい。
I want to laugh.
笑いたい！
I want to laugh!
笑ってたい。
I want to keep laughing.
笑ってたい！
I want to keep laughing!
Yeah!
笑ってたい...
I want to keep laughing...
イェーイ！
Yay!
どうもどうも！
Hello, hello!
お疲れ様でした！
Good job out there!
こんにちは！
Hello!
いや、まさかの。
Wow, what a surprise.
イェーイ！
Yay!
まさかの委員長。
I can't believe the Class President is here.
委員長に来てもらいました！
We had the Class President join us!
こんにちは！
Hello!
起立、気を付け、月ノ美兎です。よろしくお願いします！
Rise, attention, I'm Tsukino Mito. Nice to meet you!
イェーイ！
Yay!
もうね、今回イノタクさんをこうして...
Well, this time we invited Inotaku-san...
...DJブースにお呼びしてDJをね、
...to the DJ booth to do a DJ set,
してもらうことになったんですけども。
which he agreed to do.
いやいや、いつもお世話になっております。
No, no, thank you for always taking care of me.
こちらこそ。ありがとうございます。
The pleasure is mine. Thank you.
いつも...
Always...
あ、なんかあの、背景が面白い感じになってますけど。
Oh, the background has turned into something interesting.
なんか、走りたい感じの。
It makes me feel like running.
あ、走ってます。あー、準備して。
Oh, he's running. Ah, he's getting ready.
あ、こういう感じの。
Oh, like this.
おいしい！
That's great!
これがもうリハの時からずっと面白そうなんですよね。
This looked like it was going to be fun ever since the rehearsal.
これ絵面が良くて。
The visuals are great.
そう、これ絶対してほしいって。
Yeah, I definitely wanted to do this.
でね、このね、DJをやってもらおうかなってなった時に、
And when we decided to have him do a DJ set,
あのアンクラ歌いてぇなと思って。
I thought, 'I want to sing Anti Gravity Girl'.
おおー。
Ohhh.
で、歌うんならちょっと委員長見てぇなと思って。
And if I'm singing it, I thought I'd like to see the Class President.
急遽来ていただくことになりました。
So she joined us on short notice.
初めて聞きましたよ、私以外が歌うアンクラ。
It's the first time I've heard someone other than myself sing Anti Gravity Girl.
あ、そうかもな。
Oh, that might be true.
緊張するじゃん！
That makes me nervous!
いや、しかもめっちゃ難しい！
No, and it's super difficult!
難しいですよね。
It is difficult, isn't it?
めっちゃ難しい！
Super difficult!
誰が悪いんだろう？
I wonder who's to blame?
あ、カメラのズームの感じおかしいですね。
Oh, the camera zoom seems a bit off.
俺かな？
Is it me?
全部大体イノタクが悪い。
It's mostly all Inotaku's fault.
まあ、それはしょうがない。認めましょう。
Well, that can't be helped. Let's admit it.
本当にですよ。
Exactly.
感じてます。私もステラステラとか、あのミドグラでお世話になってるんですけど。
I feel it. I've also been helped with Stellar Stellar and MGO,
大体あの、高難易度なんで。
and they're usually high difficulty.
いや、ですわね。
Yeah, right.
もうなんか、恐ろしい回だな。
It's like a terrifying episode.
大体イノタクが悪い。
It's mostly Inotaku's fault.
吊るし上げの会が始まりました。
The public execution meeting has begun.
はい、で、まあここは結構会うの久しぶり？
Right, and it's been a while since we met here?
そう、1年ぶり。
Yeah, it's been a year.
1年ぶりぐらい。
About a year.
そうなんです。なんかあの、度々お話には出すんですけど。
That's right. Well, your name comes up in conversation from time to time.
私も一方的に出したことはあって、名前を。
I've also brought up your name unilaterally.
私もある。
Me too.
でも、やっぱ配信上で二人で並んだことはなかった。
But we've never actually stood side-by-side on a stream.
あんまりない。
Not really.
あ、そっか。初ではないけど。
Oh, right. It's not the first time, though.
そう、初ではない。あの、Vかにていうイベントで。
Yeah, not the first. In that event called V-Kani.
はいはい。
Right, right.
そう、一緒にね、トークを。
Yeah, we did a talk together.
フジテレビ。
Fuji TV.
そう、フジテレビ。出ましたからね。
Yeah, Fuji TV. We were on it.
トークをさせてもらったきり、あんまり喋ってもないし。
Since we did that talk, we haven't talked much.
そうなんですよね。
That's true.
あ、そうだ。私が逆凸に...
Oh, that's right. I was going to do a reverse-call...
...呼ぼうとしたんだけど、その時ちょうどね。
...and invite you, but just then,
そうそう、喉の方がって感じで。
yeah, it was when your throat was...
まだ喋れないんで、っていう感じで。
like, 'I still can't speak yet'.
でも、めちゃめちゃ行きたかったんすよ。
But I really, really wanted to go.
逆凸見たかった。
I wanted to see the reverse-call stream.
ほんとに。ガチで。
Exactly. Seriously.
すぎて、あの、喋れないけど行っていいですか？って言おうと思った。
I was so... like, I almost asked, "I can't talk, but can I go?"
すごい空気になりますよ、それ。
That would've created a weird atmosphere.
あの音声機能を使って、今日は、おめでとう、ございます、みたいに...
Using the text-to-speech function, like "Congratu-lations for today..."
それもちょっと気になったな。
I'd have been curious about that too.
美兎ちゃんなら許してくれるかなって思った。
I thought Mito-chan would forgive me.
委員長の配信っぽい感じ。
That feels like a stream by the Chairperson.
ねえ、確かにそうですね。
Yeah, certainly.
あれ、ここはどれくらいぶりなんですか？
By the way, how long has it been since we were together here?
いや、多分2年ぶりじゃないかな。
Well, probably about two years.
2年！
Two years!
あのアルバムのリリースパーティーで、DJそれこそね。
At that album release party, as a DJ, exactly.
うわ、そ、そんな前？
Whoa, was it that long ago?
そんな前？ってなっちゃう。
Makes you go "That long ago?"
2020年だったな、あれ確か。
That was 2020, I think.
うわー...
Whoa...
その時にアングラを流した。
That's when I played Angura.
流した流した。
Yeah, played it.
で、委員長がイエーイだけ。
And the Chairperson just went "Yay!"
そう、言ってたかな？確か。
Yeah, did she? I think so.
そうなんだ。
Is that so?
あとは踊りまくって。
After that, she just kept dancing.
踊ってたの？
She was dancing?
息が切れるくらい。
Until she was out of breath.
なんかアニクラのオタクって言われてました、SNS上で。
People on SNS were calling her an anicla otaku.
そうそう。
Exactly.
それ以来会ってないんですか？
We haven't met since then?
それ以来会ってない。
Haven't met since then.
そうだと思う、多分。
I think so, probably.
へー！
Whoa!
いや、その2000何年とかと言えば、すいせいちゃんは、結構古参Vですよね。
Speaking of the year 2000-something, Suisei-chan, you're quite a veteran VTuber.
あ、そうなんです、実は2018年の3月デビューでございまして。
Ah, yes, actually, I debuted in March 2018.
最初個人勢でね。
Starting as an independent.
はい。
Yes.
私、個人勢の時から知ってたから、すいせいちゃんを。
I've known Suisei-chan since her independent days.
え、何で知るんですか？
Eh, how did you know about me?
何で知るんだろう？
How did I find out?
私の謎、一体何で...
My mystery, just how...
いや、でもやっぱ歌だと思うんですけど。
Well, I think it was your singing.
あー、ありがとうございます。
Ah, thank you very much.
いえいえ、私ももちろん知ってました。
No, no, and of course I knew.
赤子の拳！
Akago no Kobushi!
あ、出た。めちゃくちゃ昔の。
Ah, there it is. From a long time ago.
洗濯機の上で配信してます。
Streaming on top of a washing machine.
出た出た。から知ってる。
There it is. I've known since then.
なるほど、なるほど。
I see, I see.
えー、だからね、なんかその時代を思うとね、美兎ちゃんとね、こうやって歌えるって...
So, you know, thinking about that era, being able to sing with Mito-chan like this...
確かに。
Certainly.
うわー、嬉しい。
Whoa, I'm happy.
よかったっすね。
It was great.
そう、そこにバックにイノタクがいて。
Yeah, and with Inotaku there in the back.
ねえ。
Yeah.
まさかイノタクもいるとは。
To think Inotaku is here too.
面白いよね、この絵面。
This scene is funny.
バックにイノタク、おーい。
Inotaku in the back, hey!
すいせいさんの復活ライブに俺が出ていいのかっていう話もあります。
There's also the question of whether I should be appearing in Suisei-san's comeback live.
ガリ、イノタク。
Gari, Inotaku.
前のね、Vカニも、あのヨッピーさん。
The previous V-kani too, with Yoppy-san.
アナウンサーの方、いらっしゃって。
The announcer was there.
いた。
He was.
毎回なんか実写の男性を挟んで喋ってるような感じが...
It feels like every time we're talking with a real-life man in between...
実写の男性はいないといけないんですかね。
Does there have to be a real-life man?
すいませんね、本当に。
Sorry about that, really.
いや、でも見れてよかったな、この組み合わせ、本当に。
But I'm glad I got to see this combination, really.
いや、でも本当に楽しかった。
No, it was really fun.
アングラめちゃくちゃこなんで、歌わせてもらって本当にありがとうございました。
I love Angura so much, thank you for letting me sing it.
いや、こちらこそ、ありがとうございました。
No, thank you.
貴重なもん聴けたわ、めっちゃ歌上手い人のアングラ聴けて嬉しかった。
I heard something precious. I was happy to hear Angura by someone who sings so well.
やったー、ありがとうございます。
Yay, thank you.
あ、じゃあ、ミトグラの締めです。
Ah, then, here's the closing for Mitogura.
あ、本家。
Ah, the original.
ミト、ミトグラです！
Mito, Mitogura!
よろしくお願いします。
Looking forward to it.
ミトグラもミトグラも。
Mitogura, Mitogura.
遅れて担当かなんか。
Late response or something.
伴奏、まさかの。
Accompaniment, unexpectedly.
よろしくお願いします。
Looking forward to it.
ということで、今日は来てくれてありがとうございました。
So, thank you for coming today.
ありがとうございました。
Thank you.
井上さんと月ノ美兎ちゃんでした！
It was Inoue-san and Tsukino Mito-chan!
ありがとうございました。
Thank you.
またね！バイバイ！
See you! Bye-bye!
あ、じゃあ私も。
Ah, then I'll... [leave too]
なにやってもうまくいかない
Nothing I do works out
脳内は戦争だもんね
My mind is a warzone, you see
突っ立ってたって
Even if I'm just standing here
なにやってもうまくいかない
Nothing I do works out
愛して、愛して
Love me, love me
なにやってもうまくいかない
Nothing I do works out
最大級世は手抜きと
The world is full of laziness
言ったことあるっけ
Have I ever said that?
なにやってもうまくいかない
Nothing I do works out
はぁん
Haan
ほんら見て来いでしょうが
You should see it for yourself
放っておいたらインスパイア
If left alone, it's inspiration
魔術が飛び交うフィールドで
In a field where magic flies around
たんとオリジナリティだかなんだか
Plenty of originality or whatever it is
模索していけって
Keep searching for it
いばらでバラバラの脳内
A mind torn apart by thorns
整合したかもわかんない
Don't know if it's even integrated
お坊ちゃまが強化されてんだ
The young master is being powered up
どうかしてるよなんて
Going crazy, they say
そっちのセリフような
That's more like your line
まあ良いから全部聞き流してくださいどうか
Well, it's fine, so please just ignore it all
大好きだったものまで嫌いになりそうな気がした
I felt like I was going to hate even the things I loved
なにやってもうまくいかない
Nothing I do works out
脳内は戦争だもんね
My mind is a warzone, you see
突っ立ってたって
Even if I'm just standing here
なにやってもうまくいかない
Nothing I do works out
愛して、愛して
Love me, love me
なにやってもうまくいかない
Nothing I do works out
最大級世は手抜きと
The world is full of laziness
言ったことあるっけ
Have I ever said that?
なにやってもうまくいかない
Nothing I do works out
正気には戻りはしない
I won't return to sanity
段々とさ気づいてた同化してたんだ
Gradually, I realized I was assimilating
正気には戻りはしない
I won't return to sanity
どうして？どうして？
Why? Why?
あとちょっとで乗り出し
In just a little bit, I'll set out
乗客はヴァンパイアだもん
The passengers are vampires, you see
ねじっといたって
Even if I stay still
なにやってもうまくいかない
Nothing I do works out
はぁん
Haan
そうか気づいて傷ついてスローダウン
I see, I noticed, I got hurt, and I slowed down
あっという間に折衷案
A compromise in the blink of an eye
めちゃくちゃフルテンです
It's a complete mess, full blast
ダンス ダンス ダンス
Dance, dance, dance
踊れ
Dance!
ドレミファジパーティぶっ壊して
Let's wreck this Doremi-fuzzy party
しらばくれ尽くせ
and play dumb to the fullest.
（笑）
((Laugh))
一般ピーポー連呼せえ電光石火で
Chant 'ordinary people' at lightning speed,
テキパキのネタもはや前方後円墳
this efficient gag is already an ancient tomb.
独り占め 飽きちゃった 何時まで 何時まで
Monopolizing, got bored, until when, until when?
なにやってもうまくいかない 全然戦争なんだもんね 突っ立ってたって
Nothing I do goes well, it's a total war after all, even if I just stand there.
なにやってもうまくいかない 愛して 愛して
Nothing I do goes well, love me, love me.
なにやってもうまくいかない 第三次世界 泣き言は言わず
Nothing I do goes well, World War III, without saying a whine.
なにやってもうまくいかない なあに
Nothing I do goes well, what is it?
なにやってもうまくいかない 全然凶暴なんだもんね ぱーただって
Nothing I do goes well, it's totally ferocious after all, even in parts.
なにやってもうまくいかない 愛して 会いたいんです
Nothing I do goes well, love me, I want to see you.
なにやってもうまくいかない
Nothing I do goes well.
心配してるフリしても もう気付いてるよ
Even if you pretend to worry, I've already noticed.
なにやってもうまくいかない なにやってもうまくいかない
Nothing I do goes well, nothing I do goes well.
なんにもやってないだけじゃない？
Isn't it just that you're not doing anything?
見せてほしい
I want you to show me
夢の続き待って 世界
Wait for the continuation of the dream, O world
溺れていたの
I was drowning
海よりも深い はじめまして
Deeper than the sea, nice to meet you
追いかけて掴んだのは
What I chased and caught
残酷な熱も 私は
Even the cruel heat, I...
歩く
walk...
水底 雨よ止まないで 恋してたんだ
At the bottom of the water, rain please don't stop, I was in love
潰れた声からして 愛してますと
From my crushed voice, saying "I love you"
叫んだんだ
I shouted it out
想えば想えば すれ違っていたの
The more I think about it, we were passing each other by
世界
O world
ねじ曲がっていた 事実も心も
The facts and even my heart were all twisted
塗り潰してさ
I painted over them all
無理だとは分かってても
Even though I knew it was impossible
無理して笑って 傷ついてしまうの
Forcing a smile, I only end up getting hurt
伝わらない現実に ただ合わせたと
Just adjusting to a reality that doesn't reach you
強がった
I acted tough
涙とまらないのは 明日が痛い 痛、痛、痛いんだ
The reason my tears won't stop is because tomorrow hurts so much
落としたナイフ 私にはもう
The dropped knife, for me already
掴めない
it's impossible to catch
声なき今 いっそ 終わりにでも
Now that I'm voiceless, I'd rather it just come to an end
なっしまえ しまえ
just let it be, let it be
Yeah, I think that...
...it's just a small lie.
言い訳が 欲しかっただけなの
I just wanted an excuse
王子様 奇跡も恋 魔法のキスも
Prince, miracles, love, and even a magic kiss
必要なかった
weren't necessary at all
幸せな夢よ 消えないで
O happy dream, please don't disappear
恋してたんだ
I was in love
泣き出しそうなんて いっそ 終わりにでもなってしまえ しまえ
Feeling like I'm about to cry, I'd rather it just come to an end, an end
分かったの 私は
I've realized that I...
恋してたってなくちゃ
...had to have been in love
恋も痛みも全部受け止めていたいから
Because I want to accept all the love and the pain
想いよ
O thoughts
届いてよ 物語が終わる前に
Reach out, before the story comes to an end
想いよ
O thoughts
愛してますと 叫ぶんだ
I'll shout that I love you
想いよ
O thoughts
愛してますと 叫ぶんだ
I'll shout that I love you
見せてほしい
I want you to show me
夢の続き待って 世界
Wait for the continuation of the dream, O world
溺れていたの
I was drowning
海よりも深い
Deeper than the sea
…り
...ly
はじめまして
Nice to meet you
Andromeda
作詞・作曲：ナノウ
Lyrics/Composition: Nanou
愛された記憶もないのに
Even though I have no memories of being loved
愛される温もりだけは知っていた
I somehow knew the warmth of being loved
生まれてきたその瞬間から
From the very moment I was born
誰かの手 求め生きてきたんだ
I've lived my life searching for someone's hand
嗚呼 伸ばした手
Ah, the hand I reached out
崩れ落ちた 砂のような
Crumbled away like sand
この思いが 胸にあるうちは
As long as these feelings remain in my heart
どこまでも 行けるはずなんだ
I should be able to go anywhere
声を消したんだ
I silenced my voice
終わらない夜には
In the never-ending night
独りきりの朝には
In the lonely morning
隣で笑うように
So I can smile by your side
涙が零れないように
So the tears won't overflow
孤独に輝いた
The star that shone in solitude
独りぼっちの星が
All alone by itself
ここにいるよと叫んで 歌になった
Cried out "I'm right here" and became a song
誰かがそれを綺麗と言った
And someone called it beautiful
わけもなく 泣きたくなるような
The kind of feeling where you want to cry for no reason
虚しさと 寂しさだけを 打ち寄せては
As nothing but emptiness and loneliness wash over me
火をつけてさ 温め合うんだ
We light a fire and warm each other
もう二度と 隠れてしまわないように
So we'll never have to hide away again
ねえ 正解とか 間違いとか
Hey, things like right and wrong
今は何一つ
Right now, not a single thing
分からないけど 一つだけ
Do I understand, but there's one thing
確かなのは
That is certain
私がいるってことだけ
And that's simply that I am here
近づいた分だけ
The more I got close
離れてゆく夢さえ
The further the dream drifted away
今ならその迷いごと 笑える気がするから
Even those doubts, I feel I can laugh at them now
孤独に輝いた
The star that shone in solitude
手と手を合わせて
Let's join our hands together
一人じゃないと叫んで
Crying out that I'm not alone
歌になった
And it became a song
誰かがそれを綺麗と言った
And someone called it beautiful
あなたの頭上に
Above your head
今も降りかかる
Still falling even now
悲しみを溶かす
Melting away the sadness
光になりたい
I want to be the light
恒久の痛みも 一緒に
Even eternal pain, together
描いてゆく空
We'll paint across the sky
教えて
Please tell me
終わらない夜には
In the never-ending night
独りきりの朝には
In the lonely morning
隣で笑うように
So I can smile by your side
涙が零れないように
So the tears won't overflow
孤独に輝いた
The star that shone in solitude
独りぼっちの星が
All alone by itself
ここにいるよと叫んで
Cried out "I'm right here"
歌になった
And it became a song
いつか誰かの夜を照らすように
So that one day it may light up someone's night
照らせるように
So that it can light the way
ありがとうございましたー
Thank you very much!
ということで、えー、カバーエリアがあって
And with that, we had the cover section...
アンドロメダ歌って
where I sang Andromeda.
おー、もうなんかここまでもう11曲ぐらい
Wow, I've sung about 11 songs up until now...
ま、10曲ぐらい歌ってるんですけれども
...well, about 10 songs.
そろそろね、もう時間も時間ですので
It's about that time, so...
告知の方を皆さんにお伝えしたいと思います
I'd like to share some announcements with everyone.
さあ、告知は何かな？何かな？
Now, what could the announcements be? What could they be?
VTRがあるそうです。どうぞ！
Apparently there's a VTR. Here it is!
星街すいせい
Hoshimachi Suisei
重大告知
Important Announcement
2023.1.25
2ndアルバム発売決定！
2nd Album Release Decided!
Ayase / ケンカイヨシ / じん / ナナホシ管弦楽団 / MI8k / 宮田‘レフティ’リョウ
Ayase / Kenkaiyosi / Jin / Nanahoshi Orchestra / MI8k / Ryo 'Lefty' Miyata
SPECTER
2022.11.4 22:00より予約受付開始
Reservations start 2022.11.4 at 22:00
ということで、2023年1月25日
And so, on January 25, 2023...
星街すいせい2ndアルバム「SPECTER」の発売が決定しましたー！
the release of Hoshimachi Suisei's 2nd album 'SPECTER' has been decided!
イエーイ！
Yay!
今年3月にリリースした「TEMPLATE」を始め
Starting with 'TEMPLATE' released this March,
今回も超豪華な作家さんたちに作曲をお願いいたしました
I've asked a super luxurious group of creators to compose for this album as well.
全11曲が収録される予定でございます
A total of 11 songs are scheduled to be included.
えーと、こっち、こっち、あ、こっち、ここです！
Um, over here, no here... ah, here! It's here!
こんな豪華作家陣です。わー、ありがとうございます！
Such an amazing lineup of creators. Wow, thank you so much!
ちょっとね、「SPECTER」っていうのが
About the title 'SPECTER'...
どういう意味なのかは、アルバムを聴いてみて察していただければ…みたいな
I hope you can guess the meaning after listening to the album.
ちょっとかっこいい寄りの曲多めで
It has quite a few cool-sounding songs...
ロックっぽい曲を収めたアルバムになっておりますので
...and it's an album filled with rock-style tracks.
このあと22時から各CDショップや
Starting tonight at 10 PM, at various CD shops and...
ホロライブオフィシャルショップにて予約が開始されます！
...the Hololive Official Shop, reservations will begin!
ぜひ予約してください。よろしくお願いします！
Please do make a reservation. Thank you!
ちなみに先行予約者限定の店舗特典はこちら
By the way, here are the store bonuses for early reservations.
わ、いっぱいある！見てね。言わない、見てね
Wow, there's so many! Take a look. I won't list them, just look.
はい、詳しくは概要欄やTwitterチェックしてください。はい！
Please check the description or Twitter for details. Okay!
ということで重大告知はアルバムでした…で終わるかと思いきや
So, that was the big announcement for the album... or so you thought.
告知がたくさんあるって話なんで、もう1個Vがあります。どうぞ！
I said there are many announcements, so here's one more VTR. Go ahead!
Hoshimachi Suisei 2nd Solo Live
SHOUT IN CRISIS
TOKYO GARDEN THEATER 2023.1.28(sat.)
2023年1月28日、東京ガーデンシアターにて
On January 28, 2023, at the Tokyo Garden Theater...
星街すいせい2ndライブ「SHOUT IN CRISIS」が開催決定ー！イエーイ！
...Hoshimachi Suisei's 2nd live 'SHOUT IN CRISIS' is decided! Yay!
ハッシュタグは #ギラギラ星街 で呟いてください
Please use the hashtag #GiragiraHoshimachi on social media.
ここ、見づらいけどこれ、わー、本当にありがとうございます！
It's hard to see here, but this... wow, thank you so much!
やっと2回目やることができました。ありがとうございます！
I finally get to do a second one. Thank you!
いつもね、私が皆さんに運営さんに
I've always been telling everyone to...
お問い合わせをしてくれって言ってたんですけど
...send inquiries to the management.
きっとたくさんお問い合わせをしたので、これができることになったんでしょう
I'm sure because of all those inquiries, this became possible.
本当に皆さんありがとうございます！
Thank you all so much!
気合を入れてね、準備頑張っておりますので、ぜひよろしくお願いします
I'm working hard on the preparations, so please look forward to it.
また、協賛でですね、株式会社ブシロードと
Also, for the sponsors, Bushiroad Inc. and...
みるハコ by JOYSOUNDさんが決定しました。ありがとうございます！
...Miruha by JOYSOUND have been decided. Thank you!
続いて皆さんが気になるチケットのお知らせです
Next, the ticket information that everyone is curious about.
現地会場チケットは指定席と学生割チケットを販売します
Venue tickets will be available for reserved seats and student discounts.
受付期間は、えー今日このあとですね、22時から11月13日23時59分まで
The application period is from 10 PM tonight until 11:59 PM on Nov 13.
かなり短いのでね、応募のご準備をどうぞよろしくお願いいたします
It's a very short window, so please get ready to apply.
また、学生割引チケットはこの機会しか受け付けませんので、
Also, student discount tickets are only available at this time,
学生の皆さんはですね、お得に手に入るこの機会をぜひ逃さぬようよろしくお願いいたします。
so students, please don't miss this chance to get them at a great price.
さらに、配信チケットも販売しておりますので、
Additionally, streaming tickets are also on sale,
チケット抽選外れた人とか、遠方で来れないよっていう人はぜひこちらも買ってください。
so for those who missed the lottery or can't make it from far away, please buy these.
詳しくは概要欄、公演サイト、各販売サイトをチェックしてください！
Check the description box, the concert site, and each sales site for details!
いや〜、盛りだくさんですね。
Wow, that's a lot of announcements.
まさかアルバムとライブ、どっちも発表されるなんて、みんな思わなかったでしょ〜？
I bet you didn't think both an album and a live show would be announced, right?
そして、ここでもう一個あります！
And I have one more thing!
以前から情報が公開されていた、ねんどろいどフィギュアについて、受注開始日が決定しました！こちら！
The pre-order date for the Nendoroid figure, which has been teased before, has been decided! Look at this!
ねんどろいど 星街すいせい
Nendoroid Hoshimachi Suisei
わぁ〜可愛い！
Wow, so cute!
なんか原型とかがね、どっかのイベントで見れてたらしいんですけども。
I heard the prototype was shown at an event somewhere.
完成形はこのようになっております。
The final version looks like this.
わぁ、みんなが求めてたフィギュア、やっと出たよ。
The figure everyone's been waiting for is finally here!
えっとね、マイクと、あの、斧と、あと、あの、四角いブロックを4つ組み合わせた何かを持っています。
It comes with a microphone, an axe, and a tetromino made of four blocks.
ぜひこちらもね、11月11日お昼の12時から予約開始となりますので、ぜひぜひチェックしてください！
Pre-orders start on November 11th at 12:00 PM, so please check it out!
さらに、今月はですね、復帰早々ですが、11月20日20時からもう一回ね、あの、3D配信があるんですよ。
Furthermore, even though I've just returned, there will be another 3D stream on November 20th at 8:00 PM.
何をするかと言いますと、仲の良いゲストとか呼んで、アルバムやライブの追加情報を公開する予定ですので、
I'll be inviting some close guests to reveal more information about the album and the live show,
皆さんぜひ見に来てください！11月20日！
so please come watch! November 20th!
ということで、最後にアンコールとして、アルバムから新曲をお披露目しちゃいたいと思いますよ！
So, for the encore, I'd like to perform a new song from the album!
今回お披露目する曲は、なんと、作詞・作曲を田淵智也さん、編曲を堀江晶太さんにお願いした楽曲です。
The song I'm unveiling today was written and composed by Tomoya Tabuchi and arranged by Shota Horie.
この後24時からデジタル配信開始されて、この配信が終わったらMVも公開されますので、
Digital distribution starts today at midnight, and the MV will be released after this stream.
なんか「？？？」って動画があったと思うんですけど、それ！そちらもぜひご覧ください。
The video with the '???' was it! Please check that out too.
かっこいい曲になってますので、ぜひ今から聴いてくださいね！
It's a really cool song, so please listen to it now!
それでは、聴いてください！
Now, please listen!
セカンドアルバムから一曲お届けします。
I'll perform a song from my second album.
灼熱にて純情
Syakunetsu nite Junjo
What's 純情？ お口に合いますか？
What's Junjo? Does it suit your taste?
甘ったるいだけじゃ満足しないね
Just being sweet isn't enough, is it?
スタンバイはとっくに出来てるの
I've been on standby for a long time.
Just time is now, time is now
おまたせ！
Thanks for waiting!
wii-wii-woo
メーデー・エマージェンシー　こんな混戦烈土
Mayday, emergency, in this chaotic world
お姫様を探すのも人間ばっか
Only humans are looking for princesses
スワイプ・タップしても体感影響なくって
Swiping and tapping gives no physical sensation
yeah
なあ　もう鬱陶しい
Hey, it's annoying now
ノイズ全部を浚うような衝動
An impulse that sweeps away all the noise
聴いたことのない爆音で
With an explosive sound never heard before
地味　知恵　誇りっぽい　退屈全部ぶっ飛ばさせて
Blow away all the plainness, wisdom, and dust-covered boredom
不機嫌な独唱よりデカいのをくれ
Give me something bigger than a cranky solo
私にステージをくれ
Give me the stage
清濁併呑　喝采！
Good and evil together, applause!
no ego　高慢無礼
no ego, arrogant and rude
沸点に届きたい　好きに歌いたいな
I want to reach the boiling point, I want to sing as I please
語彙窮なんて大層なこと言うなよ
Don't say such grand things as running out of words
敵機撃墜で確信しちゃって
Convinced by shooting down the enemy planes
あーはー　全部ないくらい燃やしたいんだって
Ah-ha, I want to burn it all until nothing's left
狭い部屋の中で　後悔は無尽蔵に
Inside a small room, regrets are inexhaustible
ぼうぼう火照るんだろう
They must be burning and glowing
あーあー　リミットなんかブーストしてしまえ
Ah-ah, just boost the limits
純情はとうに放棄して　いつの不動画に光るものなの
I've long abandoned purity, what's shining in those still videos?
しょうがないな　ちょっと黙ろうか　道を空けろよさあ
It can't be helped, how about being quiet for a bit? Now, clear the way
世界は今　轟爆に揺れる
The world is now shaking in the explosion
wii-wii-woo
What’s 純情？ 嘘そぶいて　ずっとしらけてたいな
What's Junjo? Telling lies, I want to keep being bored
救世主の采配は多分気まぐれ
The savior's leadership is probably whimsical
とにかくどんな結果だって最高潮に passing
Anyway, no matter the result, passing at the climax
you and nothing
なあ　もう鬱陶しい
Hey, it's annoying now
誰だってどうせ不安なら　平衡的にジョーク
Since everyone's anxious anyway, it's a balanced joke
縋りついたって御生憎　結局日和見に戻るだけ
Even if you cling to it, I'm sorry, you'll just end up being an opportunist again
「何か」否定しないで　ちょっと先で待ってる
Don't deny 'something', I'll be waiting a bit ahead
なんなら私の手品でも知れ
If anything, learn my magic trick
飽き足らないなら横面なのだ　誰かがカリスマ
If you're not satisfied, it's the side of the face; someone's a charisma
危なすぎるアイズワイドショット　見たくさ見惚れてさ
An eyes wide shot that's too dangerous, I want to see, I'm entranced
妄想が全部正解にできそうじゃないか
Doesn't it seem like all delusions can be made correct?
敵機撃墜　あー　燃えろ！
Shooting down the enemy planes, ah, burn!
あーはー　前例ないけど　燃やし尽くせば
Ah-ha, there's no precedent, but if you burn it all down
思い出だけなくなって歴史になるだろう
Only memories will disappear and become history
そこに立つ私に　あーあー
To me standing there, ah-ah
不可能様もうないな
Mr. Impossible, you're no longer here
純情があられなく烈勢で　澄み切った正直と笑われても
Even if I'm laughed at for my purity being in a hopeless state of inferiority,
知ったこっちゃないんだよ　こっちのペースで波乱は続くから
I don't care, the chaos will continue at my own pace
世界は今　轟爆に揺れる
The world is now shaking in the explosion
感じるほど　昂るほど　ステージは熱くなる
The more I feel, the more I'm excited, the hotter the stage becomes
だからまだ　振り絞れよハニー　ちゃんと声は届くから
So honey, wring out more, because your voice will surely reach
あぁ、絶命、ナイスバディ
Ah, death, nice body
燃やしちゃいな、って
"Burn it all up," they say
狭い部屋の中、ぐつぐつ
Simmering inside this cramped room
心は無秩序に
My heart is in chaos
妄想してんだろう
You're fantasizing, aren't you?
Ah Ah
限界、リミットが強引にブーストして
The limit is being forcibly boosted
すっかり、燃え尽くしちゃえば
If I completely burn out
形だけじゃなく、煌めく歴史になろうぜ
Let's become a shining history, not just a shape
そこに立たせて、私に
Let me stand there
Ah Ah
不可能なんて、もう無い、情緒なんだよ
Impossible is no more, it's just emotion
それが性なんだ
That's my nature
適当な理由で朽ち果てるなよ、知らないなら
Don't rot away for some random reason
ちょっと黙ろうか、道を開けろよ
If you don't know, shut up and clear the way
Honey
灼熱を、タップ、タップ、うねる
Scorching heat, tap, tap, undulating
Ah Ah
燃え尽くして
Burn it all away
灼熱にて純情
Scorching Heat, Pure Heart